This is a work of fiction. Names, characters,
places and incidents either are products of the
author’s imagination or are used fictitiously. Any
resemblance to actual events or locales or
persons, living or dead, is entirely coincidental.
合言葉は？
合言葉は知りません
Password.
なぜなら　僕はまだ君と面識がありませんので
I don't know the password.
That's because we've yet to be acquainted.
山
Hill.
か…川？
Uh... lake?
ワ…ワ…ｗｋｔｋ
E-Exciting.
カ…カ…カモシカ
Uh... Crazy?
帰れ
Go home.
Behind the words passing by
The key of my closed heart is hidden
If setting your flag
Could save your smile
The late summer breeze
Turns into a midday squall
As we sync our wavelengths
I'm such a bad romantic
Can't even find
Any words with an edge
Still I aim for the blue sky
We can become one
As our dreams and confused tears
Draw us ever closer to the truth
That becomes our beloved
Magical keyword
It's so sad when a dream ends
喉　渇いちゃった
Darn, I'm thirsty.
Hey, could you go buy some soda?
ねえ　ちょっとジュース買ってきてくんない？
I'll pass.
お断りします
Why does my junior have to be so uncute?
かわいげのない後輩だなぁ
Don't demand stuff just because you're my senior.
先輩面しないでもらえますか
I can't stand this outdated social hierarchy mania.
そういう前時代的な上下関係はへどが出ます
Then why are you here at all?
だったら　わざわざこんなとこ来なくたっていいのに
Because this place is ideal for my purposes.
ここは僕にとっては理想的な環境ですから
今までは　隠れてM45のメンテをしなきゃならなかったので
I had to hide to do the M45's maintenance until now.
Must be hard to be a masked hero.
マスクマンは大変だね
So, did you manage to install the Kill-Ballad controls?
で　『キルバラ』の操縦システムは組み込めたの
Negotiations with Furugoori are in progress regarding that.
その件に関しては　古郡に交渉中です
I tried contacting her again yesterday.
昨日も掛け合ってみたんですけど
あの…
Excuse me...
も…もしかして　古郡！？
Could you be Furugoori?!
Nope, that's Daitoku.
いや　大徳さん
Good morning.
こ…こんにちは
Am I disturbing?
あの　お邪魔だったかな
Not at all. Thanks for coming!
そんなことないよ
来てくれたんだ
この前　八汐君が言ってくれたから
You told me I should
「一度でいいから顔を出して」って
"just drop by the club room at least once."
Ah, he's the hope of the Robotics Club,
あぁ　彼はロボ部のホープ　2年の日高昴君
second year Hidaka Subaru.
どうも
Hi.
He's always gloomy like that, so don't worry about him.
彼　愛想が悪いのは元からだから　気にせずに
Ah, so you finally confessed?!
つ…ついに　告白しちゃったあ！？
Aki, could you stop spouting nonsense?
アキちゃん　何くだらないこと言ってんの
せっかくロボ部の見学に来てくれたのに
She was kind enough to visit the club, you know.
Oh, I see!
そうなんだ　ようこそ　歓迎するよ
Welcome! Have fun on your visit!
ゆっくり見学していって
ここ　風が強いんだよね
The wind's strong around here.
I'd recommend sleeping on the runway,
滑走路で寝るのがお勧めだけど
but in this season that could be fatal, so be careful.
今の時季は昼間に寝ると死ぬから　気を付けて
Sounds like it'd feel nice.
何か気持ち良さそう
Then to our new members, Subaru and Jun!
それじゃ　新入部員の昴とジュンを歓迎して　かんぱーい
Cheers!
Cheers.
かんぱーい
C-Cheers...
か…乾杯
I'm so excited!
たぎる
でも　まさかジュンちゃんが今日のうちに入部してくれるなんてね
I didn't expect you to join today though.
Yeah, I'm also surprised myself.
自分でもびっくりしてる
平身低頭　誠心誠意　拝み倒したからね
It's all because I begged on my knees!
Prez, that's not something you should be proud of.
部長　それ胸張って言うことじゃありませんか
And? Are you fine with robots?
どう　ロボットは平気？
I didn't mind the GunPro-1.
うん　ガンつく１は平気だったみたい
それじゃあさ　晴れてロボ部員になったことだし
So now that you've joined the Robotics Club,
wanna tag along with me to the Robot Clinic?
ロボクリニックに一緒に行ってくれる？
む…無理…　それは無理
I... I can't...
I really can't...
I'm just kidding. Just kidding!
嘘　嘘　今の嘘
Don't cry!
だから泣かないで
Here, have another Skal!
ほら　スコールもう１本ごちそうするから　ねっ
If you'll excuse me, I'm leaving now.
それじゃ　僕は先に帰りますから
Already? But we haven't been standing here for three minutes!
もう？　乾杯して3分もたってないよ
Three minutes of celebration is enough for me.
3分歓迎されれば十分です
Thanks for the soda.
ジュース　ごちそうさまでした
Hey, wait! Subaru!
ちょっと待ってよ　昴
待ってってば
Wait!
君島コウ…　どこでこれを？
Kimijima Kou... Where did you get this?
宇宙ヶ丘公園　廃墟の郷土館の中
In the Space Hill Park, in the abandoned folk museum.
Have you seen the girl called Airi?
愛理って女の子を見たことは？
Mizuka, do you know her?
瑞榎さん　何か知ってるの
I do. But it's nothing as complicated as written here.
知ってるよ
といっても　ここに書いてあるような小難しい話じゃない
I've met her before.
昔　会ったことがあるのさ
I was still in high school, and Airi was Misa's friend.
私がまだ高校生のころで　愛理はミサと友達だった
それだけだよ
That's it.
With Misa?
ミサ姉と…？
ただいま
I'm home.
My bike died on me, so I had to tweak the engine.
ちょ…ちょっとバイクの調子が悪くて　エンジンいじってた
I'll wash it myself later.
後で自分で洗うから
Hey! You're here, aren't you?
いるんでしょ
Would you show yourself?
ちょっと出てきてくれないかな
Um... Are you talking to me?
あの　それは愛理に話してるんでしょうか
Can I ask you a question?
あのさ　聞きたいことがあるんだけど
Can I call you "brother" again?
お兄ちゃんって　また呼んでもいいですか
Whatever.
勝手にしてよ
Then what do you want to talk about, Brother?
じゃあ　お兄ちゃん　お話とは何でしょう
The weather?
お天気の話ですか
It's not the weather.
天気の話はいい
Oh...
そうですか…
Airi, do you know Misa? Senomiya Misaki.
愛理ちゃんさ　ミサ姉のこと知ってる？
瀬乃宮みさ希
I know Misaki! We're friends!
みさ希のことなら知ってます　お友達です
Oh? Then you hung out together?
じゃ　一緒に遊んだりしたわけ？
Yeah, long ago.
はい　昔はよく
She'd talk a lot about her friends she met in school that day.
その日学校であったことやお友達のことをよく話してくれました
Mizuka, Keiko, Mitsuhiko, Yuuichi...
瑞榎　ケイコ　ミツヒコ　ユウイチ　あき穂の話もよく聞きました
She talked about Akiho a lot too!
And Kaito too!
海翔の話も
Me too?
俺のことも？
She often talked about how she'd beat you to a pulp in games.
よくゲームでこてんぱんにしていると言ってました
And who's Kimijima Kou?
じゃあ　君島コウは　何者なの
My Master!
愛理のマスターです
He made me with his own hands!
愛理はマスターの手によって生み出されました
That noise again...
また　あの音
Airi, can you see in the darkness too?
愛理ちゃんてさ　こういう暗闇でも中が見える？
ここだと見えないです
Not here.
I see through the Iru-O, so I'm blind in unmapped areas.
愛理の目は『居ル夫。』を使ってますので
マッピングされていない所では何も見えません
Useless...
使えないなぁ
Ouch!
痛っ
Did something open?
何か開きましたか
Nope.
開いてない
But... this is...
けど…　これは
ドアだ
a door.
Hiddenhand.
ヒドゥンハンド
電源　来てるのか
This place has power?
I think this is a music player that uses magnetic cassette tapes.
これは確か　カセットテープを使った音楽プレーヤー
な…何だよ　これ
What is this?
Airi, is this machine the source of that pi-ta-ta-ta sound?
愛理ちゃん　ピーガガガって音の発信源はこの装置なの
It's pi-pi-tu!
ピピーブーです
Whatever.
どっちでもいいんだけど
Is this it?
その装置が　これ？
I can't see it.
愛理には見えてないです
Please ask Sister Centipede about it.
ゲジ姉に聞いてみてください
分かった
Okay.
アクセス確認しました　ゲジ姉モードに移行します
Access rights confirmed.
Switching to Sister Centipede mode.
ここにある機械は　いったい何なの
What's this machine?
The EGI system.
EGIシステムです
エギ？
EGI?
A device that broadcasts a signal of a certain frequency at certain intervals to space.
特定の周波数の音を　一定間隔で宇宙に向けて照射する装置です
ポケコンを通じて聞くこともできます
You can listen to it using your PokeCom.
What was Kimijima Kou trying to do on the island?
君島コウは　この島で何をやろうとしてたわけ？
That is confidential.
機密事項です
君島コウはどうして死んだの
How did he die?
マスターは殺されました
He was murdered.
Murdered? By who?
こ…殺されたって　誰に？
The referenced data has been erased.
該当データは削除されています
フラウ　誰か客が来たみたいだぜ
Frau, looks like you've got a guest!
Not answering would be bad manners!
対応しないと　よくないですよ
眼鏡男子って萌えるよね
Boys with glasses are so moe.
You're panting heavily.
鼻息　荒いぜ
ただし　私の邪魔をしようとする3次元眼鏡男子
But he's a menace trying to disturb me!
Keep away! Get back, you stalker!
てめえは駄目だ　ストーカーは帰れ
I'm Hidaka Subaru!
ひ…日高昴だ
せめて話くらい聞いてくれないのか
Won't you at least listen to what I want to say?
Reported.
通報しますた
あいつ許さない　絶対にだ
He must pay! Dearly!
I-I mean it! Reported!
ガ…ガチで通報したい件について
ガチで
Wait, please!
I just want to talk about the Kill-Ballad program you made!
古郡の作った『キルバラ』のプログラムについて話がしたいだけだ
古郡は八汐先輩とは知り合いだろ
You know Yashio, don't you?
Yashio? Ah, UMISHO,
八汐？
ああ　ＵＭＩＳＨＯ氏か
I'll be entering the Robo-One world tournament with him.
僕は今度　先輩と一緒にROBO-ONE世界大会に出る
I want to ask you to make the control program for me!
そのために　古郡にプログラムを作ってほしい
If we had that, I'm sure we could win!
それがあれば　必ず結果を出せるはずなんだ
Please, Furugoori!
お願いだ　古郡
Folk museum owner
Results
Sun Development Ltd.
Folk museum owner
Results
Sun Development Ltd.
Sun Development Ltd?
タイヨウ開発
何のために　廃墟を買い取って電気代まで負担してるんだ？
Why would they buy abandoned buildings and even pay for the electricity?
Is it related to Kimijima Kou?
君島コウとの関係は
Kimijima Kou murder
Results              (0 hits)
Enough.
やめた
やっぱり　こんなの妄想だ
This is all just some delusional guy's story.
It's pointless to try to follow it.
真面目に付き合ってもしょうがない
時間の無駄だよ　バカバカしい
A total waste of time. Stupid.
I spoke with Furugoori.
古郡と話をつけてきました
というわけで　新しく古郡こながロボ部員になりました
So Furugoori Kona is our newest member!
Applause!
拍手
って　主役が何で来ないの
But why isn't the star of the show here?!
Don't underestimate my home security.
自宅警備員　なめんな
もう　何で新入部員の下級生はこうも生意気な子ばっかりなの
Why do new members have to be so cheeky?
You heard that, Subaru?
今の　昴に向けても言ってますんで
まあ　僕としてはM45のプログラムを書いてもらうだけでよかったんですが
All I care about is that she'll write the program for the M45.
Nice try. There's a condition.
交換条件　乙
A naked photoshoot, with only your glasses on.
全裸撮影会　眼鏡だけは装備で
Of course you'll be the one in front of the cameras.
もちろん　お主が撮られる方でな
ぜ…全裸眼鏡…
N-Naked with glasses?!
そ…そんな条件交わしてない
I never agreed to any such thing!
The condition was that Yashio would help you with the cheater hunt!
八汐先輩がチーター狩りに協力するって条件だろ
Naked on the African Savannah?!
全裸で…アフリカの草原に…
Not the wild cheetah, the people who break the rules in Kill-Ballad.
動物のチーターじゃなくて
『キルバラ』でずるしてトップにいるやつらをやっつけるって意味
But you made Kill-Ballad, didn't you, Kona?
こなは『キルバラ』の作者なんでしょ
Why don't you do it by yourself then?
そんなの　1人でやればいいのに
こなって言うの　やめたげてよ
Quit that. Did you really just call me Kona?
Then how about "Frau kid"?
じゃあ　フラウ坊って呼んじゃうよ
That's good. No problem!
大丈夫だ　問題ない
We should discuss the details once though.
そんなことより　一度きちんと会って打ち合わせをしましょう
さ…さては変態ですな
You sure are a pervert.
Huh?
はあ？
I only just moved here but you expect me to let you in my room?
引っ越してきたばっかなのに　クラスメート男子を部屋に入れるとか
What is this, an eroge?
それ　何てエロゲ？
むしろ八汐先輩の部屋にそこの眼鏡が泊まり込めばいいんじゃない？
You should sleep in Yashio's room first, four-eyes!
Call ended
I think I might not get along well with her.
何かうち　あの子のこと苦手かも
She's even more difficult to handle than Subaru.
昴より扱いにくそう
I'd prefer if you didn't "handle" me.
僕は　部長に扱われるつもりはありません
That's what I'm talking about.
そういうところが扱いにくいって言ってんだよ
But this Robotics Club is quite amazing.
でも　何だかロボ部ってすごい
You're all so talented.
みんな　才能ある人ばっかりで
すごい人ばかりか　何かたぎってきた
So we're all talented? That makes me so excited!
What's exciting about that?
何で　アキちゃんがたぎるのさ
When amazing people gather, they end up making something amazing!
すごい人が集まれば　すごいものが生まれるんだよ
So let's go to the Space Candy again, all together!
そうだ　もう一度スペースアメ社に乗り込もうよ
ロボ部全員で
…って言ったのに
Or so I said,
結局　ジュンと２人だけ
but in the end it was just Jun and me.
You're already done?
も…もうできたのか
つ…つーか　72時間もあれば楽勝でしょ　JK
In 72 hours, it's easy as a pie.
You worked for 72 hours straight?
72時間　ずっと作業してたのか
Once I start working I can't sleep. That's how I roll.
一度作業に入ると　お…終わるまで寝ないのがデフォ
I-It's not like I stayed up all night for you or anything!
べ…別に　あんたのために徹夜したんじゃないんだからね
Why so monotone?
何で今　棒読み
It's quite smooth. The reactions are fine too.
スムーズだね
反応もいいんじゃない？
まったく驚きです
I'm flabbergasted. How could she do this much in a few days?
古郡がわずか数日で　ここまでのものを仕上げてくれるなんて
How was the Candy?
アメ社の方はどうだった？
「どうだった？」じゃないわよ
Don't just casually ask after bailing out on us, you guys!
2人とも来てくれなくて　でも…
But...
Impact!
インパクト　これ　これよ
This! This is the impact I wanted!
これこそ　わしが求めとったインパクトじゃ
ジュンが思いの外　気に入られて
He loved Jun even more than I hoped,
スポンサー代もらえることになっちゃった
so they're gonna sponsor us!
Now we can complete it!
これで　この子を完成させることができる
We should put a star on its back.
まずは　ガンヴァレルの腰に星形を入れるんだ
And personally I'd say we should totally remake the scarf too.
あと　個人的にマフラーは絶対再現したいと思ってるんだよね
You're almost shining.
輝いてるね
やっぱり　夢とか打ち込んでいるものがある人はきらきらしてる
People with dreams to work toward are really shiny.
My dream's over though.
私の夢は終わっちゃったから
What's wrong?
どうしたの
Nothing.
な…何でもありません
More importantly, help me with the M45's test battle.
そんなことより　M45のテストバトルに付き合ってください
This really makes me shiver with excitement...
やっぱり　しびれるなぁ
You're kinda rude, Subaru, but the pile bunker is pretty cool.
昴は生意気だけど
あえてパイルバンカーを採用したところは好感持てるよ
I would've expected you to only like swords or hammers.
てっきり　部長が好きな武器は剣とかハンマかと思ってました
Geez! And here I tried to be nice and praise you.
もう　せっかく人が褒めてあげてるのに
Are you ready?
準備はいい？
いつでもOK
Anytime!
生意気な口利いてられるのも今のうちよ
I'll make you regret your rudeness!
I'll beat you to a pulp in 3 seconds!
3秒で片付けてやる
Aki, we all know you have no chance to win.
アキちゃん　それ　かませ犬フラグ
Then let's go!
それじゃ　いくね
Ready, fight!
レディー　ファイト
Go!
いっけえー
そんな正面から接近していいわけ？
You shouldn't just run at him head on...
I trust my speed!
スピード重視
Once more!
もう1回　食らえ　タネガシアッパー
Tanegashi Uppercut!
You're so weak, Aki. Had enough yet?
弱いね　アキちゃん　まだやる？
こうなったら
In that case...
A shot of youthful impulse and whim!
疾風怒濤の元気一発　タネガシアクセルインパクト
Tanegashi Accel Impact!
それ　叫びたかっただけでしょ　アキちゃん
You just wanted to shout that, didn't you?
Stepping aside's no fair!
よけるなんて　ずるい
Jun, stop it! Catch it!
ジュン　止めて　追い掛けて
Y-Yes!
は…はい
Jun's quite fast! That's the karate training for you.
ジュンて足速いね　さすが空手部
Let's have her catch it every time I use the Tanegashi Accel Impact.
今度からタネガシアクセルインパクトを使ったときはジュンに追い掛けてもらおう
Aki, are you even being serious?
アキちゃん　真面目にやってよ
This should do for the test battle anyway.
でもまあ　テストバトルとしてはこれで十分でしょう
I'm impressed at how you could master the M45's controls this quickly.
短期間で　M45をここまで使いこなすなんて
さすがですよ　八汐先輩
Oh? Was that one of your rare praises just now?
珍しく褒めてる？
Your gamer skills are top level.
先輩はゲームの腕だけは一級品です
オペレーターを頼んだのは正解だ…
You were the right choice for opera... tor...
Who's that?
誰？
What do you think you're doing?!
何するんですか　いきなり
President,
部長
don't interfere.
口を出さないでもらえますか
これは　僕と父さんの問題ですから
This is between me and my father.
Your father?!
父さん
どういうことか　説明しろ
Explain what's going on here.
夢だったから　諦め…きれなくて
It was my dream. I couldn't give it up.
何が夢だ
Your dream my ass!
Two years ago you promised!
お前は2年前　自分で約束したんだ
You said you'd give up on robots!
もうロボットは全部捨てると　俺の後を継いで漁師になると
That you'd become a fisherman like me!
Was that promise a lie too? Was it?!
あの約束も嘘だったということか
That's not it...
そんなんじゃ…
Then what's this?!
だったら　これは何だ
What's this shit!?
こんなもの
No! Stop!
駄目　やめてください
For you it might be just a toy, but it's alive!
あなたにとってはおもちゃかもしれないけど　生きてるんです
Subaru put all his heart into making it, so it's alive!
昴の思いが込められて　この子は生きてる
If you hurt it, you're hurting Subaru!
この子を傷つけることは　昴を傷つけるのと同じことです
President,
部長　口出しはしないでくださいと言ったはずです
I told you not to interfere.
Subaru...
昴
We're gonna have a long chat about this at home.
話は帰って　ゆっくり聞かせてもらう
I'm leaving.
ということなので　帰ります
Dispose of the M45 however you want.
M45は適当に処分しておいてください
処分って
You mean get rid of it?
いいんです　もう僕の夢は終わったんで
It's fine. My dream is over.
失礼します
Excuse me.
夢が終わっちゃったら　寂しいよ
A dying dream is too sad.
あき穂ちゃん
Akiho?
Aki, is it the spasms?
アキちゃん　発作？
Aki? Aki?!
アキちゃん
The blinding light of childhood memories
Turns the scenery of my dream
Into monochrome as it lies forgotten
And vanishes from my eyes
But you've always been
Looking straight at the future
And you paid the price in tears
So we turn our hesitation
Into strength by the power
Of our connected hearts
Feel it! These overflowing emotions
For that someone in the sunset
I'll use what little courage I have
And overcome the rage of the wind
Because I want to protect you
Now
it won't
bite
anymore!
Did it bother you that much...
Tune in next week too!